a new agenda car nicolas i needa this
language is more popular than java in
that python it's a language that just by
understanding it will help you so much
when building a web related product also
it's a great on the resume and it could
save you so much on a technical
interview the crazy part is that is not
even a programming language this
language that I'm talking about is SQL
yes SQL is more popular than Java in the
Python in the mind-blown thing is that
some full-stack developers have never
ever ever written a single line of SQL
code SQL means a structured query
language it is a language specifically
designed to talk to databases as you
know almost everything needs a database
databases are where we store our data so
we need to understand as developers how
to actually talk to letter basis this is
when SQL comes in there are two
categories of databases relational
databases in non-relational databases
also known as SQL and non SQL on the SQL
corner we have stuff like MySQL
PostgreSQL SQLite and on the know SQL
corner we have things like like MongoDB
dynamo DB and couchdb on this video I'm
not gonna make a comparison between no
SQL and SQL but if you want that video
leave it on the comment because it's a
really fun fight to have SQL databases
have been the default choice for most
companies and most use cases
most companies governments Bank
Enterprise legacy systems run on SQL
that's why a school is the industry
standard now how do SQL databases look
like in holiday work an SQL database
looks just like an Excel document so a
database has tables an Excel document
has sheet a table has rows and columns
an excel sheet has rows and columns so
let's pretend that we have a database
and the database has four columns
those are ID name
email in H and on the roads let's say we
have five users now let's take a look at
some basic SQL commands select let's say
that I want to get all the emails from
the users on the table students so what
I'm gonna do is write select email from
students and that's it as you can see I
am using select and from those to our
SQL commands but they are much just like
English I told you this is not a
programming language is a query language
and it looks just like normal English
now let's try to get the emails from the
users that are older than 21 so now we
say select email from the table students
where the H is more than 21 again this
statement looks really really much like
normal English and we can just read it
and understand what's going on now
let's get the ages of the users that
have an email that ends with never calm
so now we're going to say select H from
the table students where the email like
and then with never calm in this case we
are using this percentage sign and that
means that we are looking for something
that ends with never calm what if we
want to delete the student with the ID
number two or we'll have to do is say
delete from the table students where the
ID is the number two whatever you want
to get the students that are between 15
and 18 years old all we have to do is do
select email from the table students
where the age is between 15 and 18 as
you can see here were using select from
where between and and these are all
commands provided to us by SQL and as
you can see it's so much like English is
incredibly incredibly easy to understand
so why so many programmers avoid SQL or
they just don't know SQL the answer is
ORM this is basically a thing that takes
my favorite code for example Python code
and turn
into SQL so I write code on Python and I
get SQL our aims are used really really
often for example on Python I have the
jungle or em on laravel we have eloquent
ORM or no js' we have sacralized or type
RM these are all super super good
products and they save time the problem
is that they make the developers depend
on the RM because the developer doesn't
want to switch between Python and SQL
PHP and SQL it will be better if I could
just stay only on Python and get SQL via
my ORM now this is good because this
saves time
the problem is that people become
dependent on the oil and if something
breaks if they need something faster if
the ORM is not big enough then they
don't know what to do now this is why
every serious full-time developer should
learn SQL because eventually the ORM
might not be enough now I'm not saying
stop using orange I use orange all the
time I don't write SQL code every day
but when something breaks when the ORM
is kind of slow when there is something
I need to do what I can't do it with the
ORM I go in and I write raw SQL code and
that will be always so much better than
not knowing what to do in trying to work
around the issues keep in mind I'm not
saying that you should become an SQL
expert I'm just saying you should
understand at least how SQL works so at
least you understand what is your or I'm
doing for you this will help you
understand how databases work it will
help you model your data if you just
learn a little bit of SQL it would go a
long long way you are going to see the
benefits way way into the future thank
you so much for watching this video I
hope that you are now a little bit more
curious about SQL like I said you don't
have to be an expert you just need to
understand how it works but I promise
you the effort of learning right now is
going to pay in the long term thank you
for your support thank you for your
comments we're almost there in 100k as
always don't forget to be happy be warm
on the winter come Sameera sound hey-oh
don't forget to eat kimchi